Lately, six figure wins and six figure
losses are almost the new normal
nowadays where I can make four 500,000
in a single day and also lose it like if
nothing ever happened. But things
weren't always like this. If you would
have met me 7 years ago, I would have
asked you what type of donut and what
size coffee would you want? And uh in
that time period, I was a consecutively
unprofitable trader, a struggling trader
aspiring to be successful where I lost
$28,000 of my savings and my family's
[music] money. I was unprofitable and
doing all of this by myself. So, I
definitely understand what it takes to
go from absolutely nothing to having
major consistency and profitability from
the market. So, in this video today, I'm
going to teach you how to optimize your
current situation and how to go from
nothing to being at the level where you
want to be by using
>> [music]
>> $50. Don't underestimate the power of
what you can do with 50 bucks if you
execute things correctly and if you have
a plan. And in this video, I'm going to
give you a plan, a direction, and a
strategy how you can optimize it and
reach your first payout or your first
successful account flip. The realistic
way, the no BS way. Now, to get started,
the first thing that we need to do is
analyze your current situation and be
fully transparent and realistic about
your situation. You're not going to get
rich off of 50 bucks. You're not going
to be a profitable trader with 50 bucks.
and you're not going to have that lifech
changing dramatic shift that you're
looking for with 50 bucks. The best
analogy that I can give you is if for
example you were to be a fisherman. If
you were to go out to fish, you only
have one rod, one line, one hook, and
one bait. You really have limited
resources. If one fish hooks onto your
line and it snaps your line, you're done
for the day. So, you are going out to
the game or you're going out to go fish
in a very limited resource. So, you need
to tread carefully and be realistic and
you understand that you can't go and
catch extremely big fish with very small
bait and a line that doesn't have the
potential to reel in that fish. Trading
with 50 bucks is no different. You can't
expect to have 50 bucks be turned into a
billion dollars in 24 hours because
that's just simply not possible. You
can't expect to get a 50 bucks and buy
extremely high lever proper account and
get a payout in 24 hours. You need to be
realistic with your situation. And this
is the first and most important thing
because 99% of traders fail because they
have these over overly highly
expectations of what they can do with
their current situation. If you accept
that this is your learning and your
building phase, you will get a lot
further than you can imagine. You need
to use these 50 bucks as a tool to test
out your strategy, your risk management,
your psychological battles that you're
going to face. and most importantly your
plan. So if you actually execute these
things correctly, then you can scale
with the small profits that you make
with these 50 bucks, whether they're on
a prop firm account, whether they're on
a personal account, and I'll give this
plan for you later, but you need to have
full clearance and understanding that
this is your building moment. This is
your learning moment. This is not your
scaly moment. If you want to go out to
actually catch the big fish, you need to
go out on a boat to the deep ocean. You
might catch it from the shore, but not
with one line, one hook, and one bait.
So, now that we got that sour side out
of this out of the way, and you're still
watching this video, that's a really
good sign because it means that you're
willing to actually make a decision that
is going to slowly improve you. So, you
earn money from the markets, not make
money from the markets. If you're just
looking to make money, you will never
make money in the markets. You need to
earn it the correct way with the plan
that I'm going to share with you right
now. How to actually execute a correct
strategy with 50 bucks. how to scale
these 50 bucks to essentially a fortune
if you can do this the correct way and
how to find a pattern that consistently
repeats itself in the time and you can
use these 50 bucks to practice your
entries your scaling in on this pattern
so where then you can execute on a
bigger account. So with that being said,
let's get started. So first things
first, this is going to be step one to
the actual plan on how to execute with
these 50 bucks. Do not overtrade. This
is a quality over quantity game. I get
it. You want to gain experience. You
want to take trades. You want to feel
like you're in the game. You are not in
the game by being in the game. You're in
the game by playing the game
strategically. And you do that by
executing the correct type of trades.
Limit yourself to two positions a week.
No need for any more of that. And every
single one of these positions, you need
to risk a certain percentage depending
if you go to prop firm account or
personal account. I'm going to share
with that you later down in this video.
Write these notes down as key highlevel
notes that you can always come back to
when you're executing this plan. So,
first things first is quality over
quantity. Do not overtrade. Now, knowing
that you only have 50 bucks to trade
with, again, we have limited resources.
We have to be realistic with our
scenario. Limiting ourselves to one to
two positions a week is going to
directly by default put us in a category
of the type of trader that we are. So
when you're trading the markets, you are
a scalp trader, day trader, and a swing
trader. Swing traders typically take one
positions, maybe two positions every two
weeks. Day traders can take one to two
to three, maybe four positions a week,
and a scalper can probably take 15, 20
positions a week. You don't want to be a
scalper because a scalper is executing
too many positions that are low
risk-to-reward positions and have a very
inaccurate win rate because they're just
trying to enter a trade that can go in
and out of their position within the
first couple of hours. You don't want
that. You want a strong position.
They're following a trend and you're
just not looking for an impulse move.
So, scalping out of the picture. Swing
trading is a great approach, but the
problem is you don't want to be holding
a position for days, even weeks at a
time because it'll take a lot longer for
this 50 bucks to scale and the fees of
holding these trades overnight and
holding these trades over the weekend
might eat into your current balance. So,
it might not make sense. So, we get that
out of the picture and then we're left
right in the middle with day trading.
So, the type of trader that we are going
to be or the format of the trader that
we are is going to be what's called a
inday trader. So it's a trader that
trades every other day. So that's where
we would fall in that category of one to
two trades a week. Now an intraday
trader enters a position should hit
profit within the same day or the next
day. You cannot control the market. So
if the trade [music] doesn't get there
by the end of the day, there's nothing
that you did wrong. The market is just
simply moving at the rate that it's
moving. It's important that you write
this down. It's extremely important that
you write this down in your notes
because once you accept that trading
becomes a lot easier. You could be
following your plan, but you have
absolutely no control on how the
market's going to react to it. You just
have to be patient and let the market do
its thing. But we are approaching the
markets as a intraday trader. Now,
knowing what type of trader you are
going to be in the approach that you
have, you need to pick a pair that
you're going to be trading. Now, there
is dozens of difference of currency
pairs throughout the market. You have
your major currency pairs, which tend to
be the safest markets. They tend to be
the [music] least volatile, low fees and
quite predictable. You have the majors,
which the majors are also mainstream
markets, a little bit of a higher fees,
quite predictable, but sometimes you can
have these random spikes. And then you
have the exotics. Exotics are very
volatile pairs. They move very
aggressive and there's great
opportunity, but also great risk. Now,
the type of trader that we are trying to
be with these 50 bucks, you're not
trying to be the most aggressive trader.
You want to find patterns that are very
predictable. And what I'm going to
educate you into this video is a pattern
that happens across the entire markets,
but you want to limit it to a certain
amount of pairs that are the most
predictable. So you want to dedicate
this to the majors, the markets that
move very slow and steady and the fees
aren't out of this world. So these are
the EuroUSDs of the world, GBPUSDs of
the world, all of the major currency
pairs that are crossorrelating with one
another. And this approach is something
that we go and we find in every single
one of these markets. We don't limit
ourselves to one pair because that one
market cannot be giving us that one
pattern for a duration of 6 months
because the market is just moving slow.
So if we limit ourselves to just one
pair, we limit the opportunity of
catching this pattern that presents
itself. It's almost as if we were to
have a very specific approach on how to
fish off of a pier. In order for us to
fish off of a pier, we need low tides.
We need a nice current. And we need for
there to be a sunny day. If we limit
ourselves to one pier that it doesn't
have any of these conditions, we're
really limiting ourselves to the
opportunity to catch a fish. there's
hundreds of different peers that we can
travel to and look for that specific
condition in order for us to go out and
fish there. Trading in the markets is no
different. If we limit ourselves to one
specific market, it can have bad weather
for a period of time where we just
simply don't trade because the market
isn't moving the way it should. So, we
don't care about the actual market
itself. We care about the pattern within
the market that whenever it presents
itself, it presents itself. But we do
want to limit ourselves to the safer
markets rather than going to the higher
risk markets. It's almost like going to
a pier that is very accessible compared
to one that you have to go through climb
through some rocks and it could be a bit
higher risk getting there. So now
understanding the actual trader that
we're going to be with these 50 bucks.
What is the plan with these 50 bucks?
What do I do? I have $50. I want to make
money from the markets. Do I deposit
into a broker? Do I get a prop firm?
What is a prop firm? Which one's safer?
How can I not? Uh,
we're about to break things down. Let's
get right into it. So, this are your two
options when it comes to trading with 50
bucks. First option is you can go to a
prop firm. A prop firm you can buy an
evaluation process and you can get a
payout. Or step two, you go to a broker.
A broker you trade your own money. You
have a bit more leverage on it. You have
a bit more freedom, but you really are
limited to the type of profits that you
can make on it. Now, there's pros and
cons to both of these, and I'm going to
let you decide the plan for yourself.
I'm going to lay options out on the
table. You take the information, and you
determine what makes the most sense for
you depending on your situation. And I'm
going to tell you what I personally did
and what helped me scale. So, first
option [music] is prop firms. So, AAP is
a prop firm. I flew out to Australia,
met the CEO in person, saw their office
with over 150 employees running this
large-scale operation of a regulated
prop firm. If you guys are interested in
getting a properform account, discount
code down below. This is not an ad at
all, but I'm just being realistic
because I back their challenges because
I believe that they have some very cool
and creative stuff that would make the
most sense for the majority of the
traders. So, for example, with 50 bucks,
you can really get a two-phase challenge
with a $5,000 account. Meaning, you need
to pass an evaluation process. You need
to have your profit target be 9% for
your step one, and then your profit
target be 5% for step two. Now, this is
quite a lengthy process. I always
estimate it should take you anywhere
from 30 to 45 days to pass a two-step
challenge simply because you should take
be taking one to two trades a week if
you were just to have a basic 50% win
rate. If you make 3% then lose 1% make
3% then lose 1% make 3% then lose 1%
that's roughly the 9% in about 3 weeks.
When you look at it in that math you're
like well that's kind of doable. That's
pretty realistic. Well, that's just
phase one. Then I give you another two
to three weeks to then pass phase two.
So you have a winning position one day,
have a losing position the next day. As
long as you're profitable and you have a
good risk-to-reward, you'll be
successful. [music]
So that's for the two-phase challenge.
You have their custom day trader
challenge, which is quite cool in my
opinion because you can customize your
challenge where you're essentially
instantly funded and you get a payout on
what you have. So, if all we have is 50
bucks, we can even break this down to as
little as five bucks if you want to, but
if you want to risk the entire 50 bucks,
this is like getting an instantly funded
challenge where you have an evaluation
process for a duration of time. So, you
either have 1 hour to pass a challenge,
a 2hour challenge, a 4-hour challenge,
or an 8 hour challenge. All of these
challenges, they just slightly get
harder depending on the hours that you
pick. So, the way it works is that you
start with a $10,000 starting balance.
Whether you decide to risk 50 bucks, 300
bucks, 500 bucks, your starting balance
is always a 10k account. You decide how
long you want your challenge to be and
what you want your payout to be. So, if
you pass a challenge, you just get paid
out right away. There's no evaluation
process. There is no profit split. There
is no continuation. It's just you pass
it, you get paid, you do it again. Very
simple. It's like an instantly funded
account with a one-time payout option.
So, you can choose to either have two
times what you decided to put at stake.
You can put five times or 100 times. As
you can tell, the only thing that
changes is how much you get paid out and
your draw down and profit target. So,
for example, let's say you want to get
2x of what you risked. All you have to
do is make $99
on the $10,000 account balance without
risking without losing more than 67%. I
mean, I'm sorry, $67 and then you'll
instantly get 100 bucks payout. If you
want to go 5x where you would get 250
bucks, you have to make 133 bucks
without losing 47. You want a 10k
payout, you have to make 239 without
losing 40 bucks. So, it slightly gets a
little bit harder where you have to make
more money without losing as much money.
And if you were to change the duration
of the challenge, things get easier. If
you were to have a 1-hour challenge,
your profit target is a lot less, but so
is your draw down. If you have a higher
profit target, your profit a longer
challenge, your profit targets a lot
higher and your draw down's a lot lower.
Just a customizable challenge that I
wish I had when I got started trading in
my journey. And it's pretty cool. You
can mess with it. You can play with it.
You can see how it makes the most sense
with you. And then you also have what is
called the one-step challenge. So I'm
just laying out the options right now
that are right in front of you and you
can decide for which one makes the most
sense for you. So the other one phase
challenge, it's the exact same thing.
It's a total profit of 10% and then you
have a funded account. So, this the
benefit of both of these funded accounts
is that you could trade that funded
account continuously [music]
and continuously get profit splits from
it. Day trader challenge is kind of just
a one-time payout and that's pretty much
it. So, the beauty of it is that you get
90% profit split. You can build your
custom challenge and [music] you have a
lot less risk with a lot better leverage
with these 50 bucks. So once you are
funded with that $5,000 challenge, let's
say for that next month you would make
10%. You would essentially keep nearly
450 bucks from that 10% that you made on
the 5,000. So it makes sense to go the
funded route. The problem is that you
can be a profitable trader but still not
make money because you can probably make
on let's say this onestep challenge you
can make a total of five to six% where
you're profitable but you enter a small
little losing streak or you just break a
small rule where you risk too much for a
specific session and then you lose your
account. Just because you broke a
specific rule doesn't mean that you're
unsuccessful. By the way, this platform
has no hidden rules. I did a whole
YouTube video on this. So you guys can
go check it out. I talked to the CEO,
asked all the hard questions, and they
answered. They showed us the behind the
scenes. You guys want to go check it
out, you can see it for yourselves. I
did all the hard work before partnering
up with any prop firm because I don't
want you guys to go somewhere that is
not going to be a pleasant journey and
you simply just waste your time. So with
this prop firm, the problem is that if
you are a successful trader, it won't
show until you get a profit split. That
goes for any prop firm and any
challenge. Now, when it comes to trading
on your own personal account, there's
pros and cons. So, these are the trusted
brokers that I trade with. If you guys
would like to know more about it, link
in the description down below. I got it
asked every single video. And I feel
like sometimes people are blind. Like,
it's it's right there, you know? So, the
beauty of having your own money in your
own accounts is that if you were to win
that first position that you execute
with the 50 bucks, those profits are
yours right away. It's not like the prop
firm where you have to pass a challenge,
do it again, until you get a payout, and
you need to just follow these very
strict rules. These rules are meant to
be in place for you to not break them
and be consistent. Now, with the broker,
you are pretty much just freefor-all.
Nobody's holding you accountable.
Nobody's setting limits. Nobody's
watching or caring what you're doing.
you're just taking trades at your own
free will, which could be good, but also
very bad because we all know when it's
us by ourselves in our dark room in
London session executing a trade, we
tend to just be impulsive. So, there's
benefits to this because you have more
buying power. So, you get north of 100
of a 1 to 500 leverage using these
brokers because you can execute trades
as if you were to have a $5,000 account
and you can have instant withdrawals.
So, if your first position with this $50
account, you were to make 25 or 50
bucks, you can withdraw your initial
balance and then you're basically
playing with the house money. So, at
that point, there's nothing at risk. And
the beauty and also double-edged sword
is that there's no rules. If nobody's
watching you accountable, who's going to
make sure that you're doing things
correctly? Nobody but you. And this is a
whole other topic, but these are just
the options that I'm laying out right in
front of you. what I would personally do
and this is what I did. I went I got
funded. I passed an evaluation process.
After I got passed and I got [music]
funded, I used those profits and that
knowledge and that experience to then
use my personal accounts to scale. So, I
would personally start with attempting
to pass a challenge, get funded, get
that payout, use those profits to go and
trade my personal account. I would not
go and use that to go get a bigger
challenge simply because you fall in
that same realm. You got real money that
you just made and you're putting it back
into a challenge where you can
essentially be profitable but still fail
because you broke whatever rule or just
because you had a small losing streak
where in your personal account you can
have a losing streak but you can still
have your account and have equity in it
as long as you did not overlever your
account. So, let's hypothetically say
that you decide to take the exact same
journey that I did. That journey is very
simple. You would go ahead and get your
first challenge. I would probably get a
one-step challenge. So, I would come
here, go to the one-phase challenge. I
would go and select buy now to get the
challenge. And you would use the coupon
code Alex G20. You would apply that
coupon code and you would get discounted
the 20% where you're left with $55.
almost at the 50 bucks point, but you
would get your challenge and you would
attempt to pass this evaluation process
with the strategy that I'm about to
share with you. And once again, you
would use this profits that you would
make once you're funded to then go back
and deposit into your personal accounts
and then you scale exactly how I've just
mentioned. So, with that being said and
understanding that plan, let's now go
into the actual pattern that we're going
to be looking for so we can execute
[music]
to pass this challenge and then get our
payout so we can scale our personal
account. Now, we are at the end of the
preparation to actually execute the plan
with these $50. And the new plan and the
new approach begins. The new journey is
at this very point right here where
you're going to execute a very specific
pattern [music] continuously throughout
the duration of this challenge. and only
stick to that. The problem with 99%
traders as to why they don't succeed is
because they don't stick to a plan. They
get tempted. They get FOMO. They get
greedy because they just want to take
every possible opportunity that they can
find in the market. The market rewards
the people that make the right
decisions, not the ones that execute
every single decision. You get rewarded
for taking the right trade. And this
right trade might not present itself
right when you're available. might not
present itself today or tomorrow or the
day after and you need to be patient and
wait for this pattern to present itself.
You get rewarded for taking the right
trade. The challenge is AAP does not
care if you are executing as many
possible positions as you can can when
the hour that you are free to trade.
They reward you when you win and you win
by taking the right trade. And this is
the right trade. You just need to be
very patient to have this trade appear
and execute. So the pattern that we're
going to be looking for with this is
going to be the famous head and
shoulders. So the head and shoulders is
going to be the only pattern that you
are going to execute when it comes to
this account that you're trying to scale
with these 50 bucks. You're not going to
break your plan for anything. Head and
shoulders is a very simple pattern and
it is what is called a reversal pattern.
So this pattern once you are having a
bullish markets and you see it means
that it's going bearish. Once you're
having a bearish market and you see it,
it means that it's potentially about to
go bullish. So this works very simple. A
market that is bullish is heading to the
upside. It's creating structure. Let me
actually do this right here. A market
that's heading to the upside is heading
to the upside creating highs and lows,
highs and lows, highs and lows. And then
it'll do a formation like this where
might almost come as a disguise, right?
Because everything up to this point
looks good. This looks like a market
that can just easily create another
higher high. You can never predict a
head and shoulders is forming until it's
actually formed. Anybody that
anticipates a head and shoulders without
experience is jumping the gun a little
bit and they end up taking the wrong
trade and losing. [clears throat]
Because in a position like this, it's
impossible for you to tell that this
next right shoulder is going to be that
reversal for this market. This just
looks perfect to continue to head to the
upside. And that's exactly what this
did. This actually continued to head to
the upside and create a new high. So
this market is very much bullish. Now
the moment that we
create this what is called the potential
right shoulder, this is where we start
looking to be interested in this
position. Now, once we can tell that
this impulsive move is not going to
create that new high and it's slowing
down and it's looking like a head and
shoulders formation, this is when it
starts spiking our interest and we start
looking for this opportunity. Now, we
don't enter the position off of the
right shoulder because that is not a con
that is not a confirmed head and
shoulders right now. For all we know,
this could just be creating more
structure here before heading to the
upside and you just got faked out
because you entered on the position way
too early. So, you need to be interested
in entering this position once you have
a confirmed head and shoulders. How do
you have a confirmed head and shoulders,
you may ask? Very simple. This market is
being moved with market structure. This
is the higher high point and then this
is the higher low point right here. The
head and shoulders as if if you guys are
paying attention is a reversal pattern.
Reversal pattern also means shift of
structure, chach, change of direction,
change of character, whatever you want
to call it. Something went from one
direction to the other. And the head and
shoulders is only confirmed once you
have that change of direction. So once
this higher low has been shifted and
this market goes from bullish to bearish
is exactly when this will be a valid
head and shoulders. Now this is a
bearish market. This turns into the new
lower low and this will turn into the
new lower high. Now we are game. Now we
have an actual head and shoulders
pattern. The moment we were inside of
this higher low, if we were up to this
point right here, we are still not with
a valid head and shoulders. This is not
a confirmed shift of structure, cher,
change of direction, change of identity,
whatever you want to call it. This is
still a bullish market. Looks like a
really good head and shoulders, but it's
not a confirmed one just yet. Need to
wait for the full shift. Then this
market turns to bearish. This becomes
the new lower low. And after this
becoming the lower low, we'll have this
turn into the lower high, which is
perfect. But now we have a confirmed
bearish market. Now is when the actual
strategy begins, which is our head and
shoulders. Up to everything before this,
we were waiting for this market to
break. [music] Waiting for this to have
the push down, have the retracement,
have the push down. Now is when we
actually [music] start trading. This is
where we start to do our analysis and be
interested in entering this position.
Everything prior to this is just us
sitting here twiddling our thumbs and
just being patient. This is us sitting
at the pier with our rod in our hand, no
bait on the hook, not casting anything
out. We're just sitting there waiting
for the current to start moving and for
the sun to come out. As soon as the sun
comes out and the current starts moving
is when we start to prepare ourselves to
begin fishing. right there. We were just
at the ocean waiting for an opportunity
to have our specific strategy where we
start casting out our bait where it
starts to become worth it. If not, we're
going to risk losing the bait, which is
essentially lost money and it simply
makes no sense. Everything up to this
point, we're just at the pier. We're at
the market waiting for an opportunity
for everything to line up with us where
we would then to actually start to apply
our strategy. It's a very cool
perspective when you think about it
because fishing and trading really isn't
no different. We both have plans on to
what we would do when it would make
sense for us to fish. And I'm sure a lot
of people aren't successful fishermanmen
because they don't have a plan. They
just go out there and throw their bait
and never catch a fish. Uh this is
exactly why people come to the markets.
They [music] just take a trade and don't
succeed because they don't have a plan.
Right? So it's very very very similar.
So now that this market has shifted
bearish, we are game. So this is exactly
where we would then wait for this trade
to have this retracement. Come back and
retest this neckline of the head and
shoulders. And this is where we would
then execute our position where we would
put our stop-loss and then we would put
our takerit and we would just set and
forget. Now this strategy can arguably
have a 60 to 65% win rate. Sometimes
more, sometimes less. Depends how
patient you are and how well you execute
this pattern. But these head and
shoulders patterns are very predictable
and they happen all the time. So we're
going to be trading this on the major
currency pairs. And these currency
pairs, we're going to be looking for
this pattern strictly on the 4 hour. So
for this specific strategy, we're not
going to take into consideration the
higher time frames, the lower time
frames, just looking at the 4 hour to
execute this trade. So this is where I
can just go to one of my more recent
trades that I took on Euro AUD. And this
is a perfect example right here. As you
can tell, this market was bullish on the
4 hour. This market was creating highs,
lows, highs, lows, highs, lows. We went
bullish. So, as you can tell, this right
here is the higher high and higher low.
This is the high point right here. This
is the higher low point right here. And
then what we're waiting for is for the
market to shift below that higher low.
As you can [music] tell, if this is the
higher low point right here, the market
never really shifted into this point
right here. So, this is the left, this
is the head, and this is the right
shoulder. A bit ugly, you know, they all
of these aren't super pretty. Some of
them are a little bit ugly, and they
create a bit more structure, but once
you get experience with it, you can see
the overall direction happened right in
front of you. This market closed below.
We shifted, retested, entered this
position with my stop loss above the
wick, my take profit to the next
structure point. That is it. That is
your head and shoulders reversal pattern
formation. And I could have continued to
hold this position for a significantly
longer trade. But I decided to close at
my 1 to2 risk-to-reward. And that's it.
And I can just simply scroll left and
I'm sure I'm going to find endless
opportunities of these head and
shoulders that present themselves. This
is another perfect example right here.
For example, this right here is another
great head and shoulders pattern. This
market was heading to the upside,
creating that bullish structure that
we're talking about. High, low, high,
low, high, low. This is the bullish
structure. We shifted. Once we shifted,
we retested and we sold. It really is
that simple. We are looking for the
reversal pattern. We wait for the break,
enter on the retest, set, and forget.
Cannot get any simpler than this. And
believe me, I get it. There is hundreds
of different approaches that they are
out there. You have double top
formations, uh ABC patterns, you have uh
Fibonacci, like you have so many
different types of trading approaches
that you could go out and actually
execute. But we are not going to use any
of those. You need to have ton of
vision. This is just you need to be like
a horse where you're only looking at one
specific approach and sticking to that
approach every single time you go
execute the position and not get
distracted with the other opportunities
that you're executing in the market
because you're only looking for that
head and shoulders pattern. I don't care
if it's an ABC pattern, if it's a
Fibonacci, it does not matter. And once
you start to see this, it's almost kind
of hard to unsee it. It's like the red
car theory. You ever heard of it? red
car theory where if you buy a red car,
you start to see red cars everywhere.
And prior to that, you never really paid
attention [music] to red cars at all.
But now, because you're aware of red
cars because you own one, you see them
everywhere and you're like, "Dude,
everybody has a red car." This is the
exact same thing. Now that you're aware
of this pattern and to only look at for
it in the major currency pairs in the 4
hour, you can just go to any one of
these major currency pairs and go back.
Go back in time. Just pause this video
right here or do it after this video and
just go back and you're going to see
these patterns. You're going to be like,
"Wow, I have missed out on so many of
these opportunities and I have just been
over complicating trading." Yes, you
have. It's totally normal. It's part of
the game. You're here to make a
difference if you're by this point in
the video. You just need to be
consistent to this approach. Now,
understanding this very specific setup
that you need to be extremely patient
for to present itself, execute the
trade, and set forget. I want to build
for you guys a cheat sheet so [music]
you don't forget what you have to be
doing. I've seen countless amounts of
traders, they start their challenge
great, then they get impatient halfway
and then they lose it and they start
right back at square one. I don't want
that to happen to you because I want you
to succeed and I want to build you a
cheat sheet so you can actually follow
this. Now, step one on this cheat sheet,
I'm going to pop it up right here to
this side. First step is going to be to
only execute this replicable trade
setup. Be very patient. You know, it's
that head and shoulders pattern. Wait
for that to present itself. If you do
not get that trade setup, do not take a
trade. You are playing the game by not
playing the game, but by knowing when to
play the game. This is very important
that you know this. Next point is going
to be to only enter after a
confirmation. Do not enter off of an
anticipation. If you have the head and
shoulders that looks like the most
beautiful head and shoulders in the
world, if it is not a confirmed head and
shoulders, do not execute [music] that
position. You need to wait for that
position to confirm that you have
shifted. Next is going to be to use
certain psychological levels in your
favor. So sometimes when these head and
shoulders break, they are psychological
levels like for example 80,000 0.80,000
or 1.0000.
Every psychological level is extremely
key to having a stronger trade. Does it
make or break it? It's almost as if you
were to go fish and you can almost see
the fish, right? It's a doesn't mean
that the fish is going to bite your
bait, but at least you have a better
feeling that the odds [music] of you
catching that fish are there. So, just
because you have to trade under or above
the psychological level doesn't mean
that you're going to win the trade, but
it's slightly better of a confirmation.
It's very key to having a higher
probability trade setup. Next is going
to be your fixed percentaged risk.
The most successful traders in the game
that have been in the game for 10 years,
they're not in the [music] game for 10
years because they won big. They're in
the game for 10 years because they never
lost big. You never lose big if you
stick to the risk management that you
need to be taking. So have a fixed
percentage [music]
on your challenge account. Make it a 1%
rule. Make it a half percent rule. This
is a marathon, not a sprint. You want to
earn your money, not make money. Very
different points. Next is going to be
have a minimum of a one to two
risk-to-reward. Do not take a trade that
is not worth the risk. You don't want to
make an even one to one of what you
risk. If you risk 10 bucks, you don't
want to make 10 bucks. You want to make
at least a minimum of 20 bucks. This is
a deal breaker when it comes to how well
you make back your losses and what will
[music] lead you to becoming a
consistently profitable trader is how
well you recover from those losses
because losses are inevitable and how
much profit is left on the table. So
this cheat sheet, take a screenshot,
write it down in your own notes, print
it out, put it next to your computer,
put it as your wall screen, do whatever
you have to do so you don't lose track
as you're taking this challenge. It is
very normal. We are human. As time goes
on on week three, week four, you can get
a little bit impatient as you're seeing
other traders on social media making
billions of dollars off of taking the
same trades as you, and you're in a
position there like, damn, I'm just
risking 1% on my 5K challenge with my 50
bucks. Well, if you were to have paid
attention at the beginning of this
video, you need to understand and be
realistic with your current situation.
Your current situation is temporary.
You're not going to be in this situation
forever if you follow the plan. If you
don't follow a plan, you're going to
stay in that same negative spiral effect
and you're just simply going to be
walking on a treadmill and not advance
forward. Because the people that are
making all this money, they stuck to a
plan where they got out of the position
that they're in right now and then they
eventually earned the position that
they're in right now. And you can do
that for yourself if you do things
correctly. And this is what I do every
single week with my students inside of
my community. I educate them on how to
stay [music] consistent with this very
same specific approach where they are
executing the trades according to the
strategy. They're engaging with other
community members and most importantly
they're taking the same trades that I am
taking. If you feel motivated and you
feel that you have a plan now to go out
to the market and pass this challenge,
imagine if you were to also have the
same pairs that I am interested in
trading every single week. Well, you can
because I do this every single week with
my students where I hop on the famous
Sunday swings where I share my top
markets that I am interested for that
very week. what markets I'm looking to
enter, whether it's a major, minor, or
exotic, why I'm interested in entering
that market, where is my specific entry
going to look like, where my stop loss
is going to be, where my take-profit is
going to be, and then we spend all week
discussing inside of the community how
this trade is playing out. And I even
have times where I review trades of my
students where I can tell them, hey, you
did this wrong here. You did this right
here. the odds of you succeeding while
having this proper guidance is just very
high and very probable of you
succeeding. We're here at my trading
floor in Miami. I have built a compound
where my students only and exclusively
come out to the trading floor. They have
access [music] to funds that they can
trade with and also learn here in
person, but this is only to my students.
If you want to learn more how to
potentially be a student, click the link
down below in the description and apply.
It's off of an applicationbased only and
you might have a chance to be part of
the community and come out to the
trading floor. With that being said,
ladies and gentlemen, I hope you guys
enjoyed this video, [music] found loads
of value. If you have to go back and
rewatch this video and write down notes,
do it. Don't get your challenge. Don't
get this account flip and try and do it
within the first 24 to 40 hours.
Understand that this is a marathon, not
a sprint. And if you execute these
things correctly for the next 3 to 4
months, you will be in a different
position that you're in right now
because now you have a plan and a very
specific approach. Thank you guys very
much for watching this video. Hit that
like and subscribe button and I'll see
you guys in the next